<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Third Conference on Computational Humanities Research on Computational Humanities Research 2022</title>
    <link>http://2022.computational-humanities-research/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Third Conference on Computational Humanities Research on Computational Humanities Research 2022</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 15 Dec 2019 11:12:14 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://2022.computational-humanities-research/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Past Events</title>
      <link>http://2022.computational-humanities-research/archive/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Feb 2021 16:05:25 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://2022.computational-humanities-research/archive/</guid>
      <description>CHR2020 CHR2020 was a three-day workshop held on November 18 to 20, 2020. The program committee and organizers accepted 29 papers, which have been published with CEUR-WS: http://ceur-ws.org/Vol-2723/. See https://2020.computational-humanities-research.org/ for more information about CHR2020.
CHR2021 CHR2021 was a three-day conference held on November 17 to 19, 2021. The program committee and organizers accepted 29 papers, which have been published with CEUR-WS: http://ceur-ws.org/Vol-2989/. See https://2021.computational-humanities-research.org/ for more information about CHR2021.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Organizers and Programme Committee</title>
      <link>http://2022.computational-humanities-research/people/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Feb 2021 15:59:28 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://2022.computational-humanities-research/people/</guid>
      <description>Programme Chairs Kristoffer Nielbo, Aarhus University Alie Lassche, Leiden University Organizers Maud Ehrmann, École Polytechnique Fédérale de Lausanne Folgert Karsdorp, KNAW Meertens Institute Mike Kestemont, University of Antwerp Alie Lassche, Leiden University Enrique Manjavacas, Leiden University Kristoffer Nielbo, Aarhus University Line Ejby Sørensen, Aarhus University Thomas Smits, University of Antwerp Melvin Wevers, University of Amsterdam Joris van Zundert, Huygens ING - KNAW Programme Committee TBA</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Important Dates</title>
      <link>http://2022.computational-humanities-research/dates/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Feb 2021 12:53:21 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://2022.computational-humanities-research/dates/</guid>
      <description>Submission deadline: Midnight (AoE), September 6, 2022
Notification to authors: October 18, 2022 Final papers ready: November 1, 2022
Conference: December 12 - December 14, 2022 </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Accepted Papers</title>
      <link>http://2022.computational-humanities-research/papers/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Aug 2020 08:55:52 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://2022.computational-humanities-research/papers/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Advisory Board</title>
      <link>http://2022.computational-humanities-research/advisory-board/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2019 21:22:17 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://2022.computational-humanities-research/advisory-board/</guid>
      <description>Tara Andrews - University of Vienna, Austria Maud Ehrmann - EPFL, Switzerland Leah Henrickson - Loughborough University, UK Mike Kestemont - University of Antwerp, Belgium Barbara McGillivray - University of Cambridge and The Alan Turing Institute, UK George Mikros - National and Kapodistrian University of Athens, Greece Kristoffer Nielbo - Aarhus University, Denmark Michael Piotrowski - University of Lausanne, Switzerland Tatjana Scheffler - University of Potsdam, Germany Ted Underwood - University of Illinois, U.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Join the Community</title>
      <link>http://2022.computational-humanities-research/community/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Dec 2019 11:12:28 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://2022.computational-humanities-research/community/</guid>
      <description>We cordially invite you and other interested parties to join the Computational Humanities Research forum! The forum serves as an asynchronous platform to discuss all ideas and questions related to computational humanities research. These can be in-depth discussions about fundamental topics and questions of the discipline, or very practical ones, for example about how best to tackle a certain technical (coding) problem. And everything in between. Come join!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Join the Community</title>
      <link>http://2022.computational-humanities-research/contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Dec 2019 11:12:28 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://2022.computational-humanities-research/contact/</guid>
      <description>Community Please join our Computational Humanities Research forum! The forum serves as an asynchronous platform to discuss all ideas and questions related to computational humanities research. These can be in-depth discussions about fundamental topics and questions of the discipline, or very practical ones, for example about how best to tackle a certain technical (coding) problem. And everything in between. Come join!
Contact For questions, ideas, or support, contact the organizers or drop us a line on the forum.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Call for Papers</title>
      <link>http://2022.computational-humanities-research/cfp/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Dec 2019 11:11:58 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://2022.computational-humanities-research/cfp/</guid>
      <description>In the arts and humanities, the use of computational, statistical, and mathematical approaches has considerably increased in recent years. This research is characterized by the use of formal methods and the construction of explicit, computational models. This includes quantitative, statistical approaches, but also more generally computational methods for processing and analyzing data, as well as theoretical reflections on these approaches. Despite the undeniable growth of this research area, many scholars still struggle to find suitable research-oriented venues to present and publish computational work that does not lose sight of traditional modes of inquiry in the arts and humanities.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
