<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Third Conference on Computational Humanities Research on Computational Humanities Research 2022</title>
    <link>http://2022.computational-humanities-research/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Third Conference on Computational Humanities Research on Computational Humanities Research 2022</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Sun, 15 Dec 2019 11:12:14 +0100</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="http://2022.computational-humanities-research/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Past Events</title>
      <link>http://2022.computational-humanities-research/archive/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Feb 2021 16:05:25 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://2022.computational-humanities-research/archive/</guid>
      <description>CHR2020 CHR2020 was a three-day workshop held on November 18 to 20, 2020. The program committee and organizers accepted 29 papers, which have been published with CEUR-WS: http://ceur-ws.org/Vol-2723/. See https://2020.computational-humanities-research.org/ for more information about CHR2020.
CHR2021 CHR2021 was a three-day conference held on November 17 to 19, 2021. The program committee and organizers accepted 29 papers, which have been published with CEUR-WS: http://ceur-ws.org/Vol-2989/. See https://2021.computational-humanities-research.org/ for more information about CHR2021.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Organizers and Programme Committee</title>
      <link>http://2022.computational-humanities-research/people/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Feb 2021 15:59:28 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://2022.computational-humanities-research/people/</guid>
      <description>Programme Chairs  Kristoffer Nielbo, Aarhus University Alie Lassche, Leiden University  Organizers  Margherita Fantoli, KU Leuven Folgert Karsdorp, KNAW Meertens Institute Mike Kestemont, University of Antwerp Alie Lassche, Leiden University Kristoffer Nielbo, Aarhus University Line Ejby Sørensen, Aarhus University Thomas Smits, University of Antwerp Melvin Wevers, University of Amsterdam  Programme Committee  Adrien Barbaresi, BBAW Ahmed Hamdi, Université de La Rochelle, L3i Alberto Acerbi, University of Bristol Alie Lassche, Leiden University Allen Riddell, Indiana University Bloomington Andreas Baumann, University of Vienna Andreas van Cranenburgh, University of Groningen Andrew Piper, McGill University Anne Kandler, Max Planck Institute for Evolutionary Anthropology Antoine Doucet, University of La Rochelle Artjoms Šeļa, Institute of Polish Language, Polish Academy of Sciences (Krakow) Barbara McGillivray, King’s College London Bruna Wundervald, Maynooth University Cerstin Mahlow, ZHAW Zurich University of Applied Sciences Christof Schoech, University of Wurzburg Clemens Neudecker, Berlin State Library Coline Métrailler, UNIL Cynthia Liem, Delft University of Technology Damien Nouvel, INaLCO David Mimno, Cornell University Eetu Mäkelä, University of Helsinki Elena Fernández Fernández, University of Zurich Elli Bleeker, Huygens Institute for the History of the Netherlands Emanuela Boros, University of La Rochelle Enrique Manjavacas, Leiden University Estelle Bunout, University of Luxembourg Federica Bologna, Università di Bologna Folgert Karsdorp, Meertens Institute Fotis Jannidis, Julius-Maximilans-Universität Würzburg Frédéric Clavert, C2DH / Université du Luxembourg George Mikros, Department of Italian Language and Literature, National and Kapodistrian University of Athens Inna Uglanova, Technical University of Darmstadt Iza Romanowska, Aarhus University Jean-Philippe Moreux, Bibliothèque nationale de France Joris Van Zundert Huygens, ING - Royal Netherlands Academy of Arts and Sciences (KNAW) Kaspar Beelen, The Alan Turing Institute Katrin Glinka, Freie Universität Berlin Koraljka Golub, Linnaeus University Kristian Gade Kjelmann, Aalborg University Kristoffer Nielbo, Aarhus University Lars Johnsen, National Libary of Norway Lauren Fonteyn, Leiden University Lauren Klein, Emory University Laurent Romary, INRIA &amp;amp; HUB-ISDL Lene Offersgaard, University of Copenhagen Manuel Burghardt, Computational Humanities, University of Leipzig Marco Passarotti, Catholic University of the Sacred Heart Marieke van Erp, KNAW Humanities Cluster Marijn Schraagen, Utrecht University Maristella Agosti, University of Padua Marten During, Luxembourg Centre for Contemporary and Digital History (C2DH) Matteo Romanello, Ecole Polytechnique Fédérale de Lausanne Maud Ehrmann, EPFL, DHLAB Melvin Wevers, University of Amsterdam Michael Piotrowski, University of Lausanne Mike Kestemont, University of Antwerp Mikko Tolonen, University of Helsinki Nikki Stevens, Arizona State University Nils Reiter, Institute of Natural Language Processing, Stuttgart University Nina Tahmasebi, University of Gothenburg Oleg Sobchuk, Max Planck Institute for the Science of Human History Rachele Sprugnoli, Università degli Studi di Parma Ramona Roller, ETH Zurich Roel Smeets, Radboud University Ross Kristensen-McLachlan, Centre for Humanities Computing, Aarhus University Simon Clematide, University of Zurich Stefan Schweter, Bayerische Staatsbibliothek München, Digital Library/Munich Digitization Center Tara Andrews, University of Vienna Ted Underwood, University of Illinois at Urbana-Champaign Thierry Declerck, DFKI GmbH Thierry Poibeau, LaTTiCe-CNRS Tim Tangherlini, Berkeley Tobias Hodel, Digital Humanities/Walter Benjamin Kolleg/Universität Bern Yann Ryan, Queen Mary, University of London Yuerong Hu, School of Information Sciences,University of Illinois at Urbana-Champaign Yuri Bizzoni, Aarhus University Zachary Stine, University of Central Arkansas  </description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Important Dates</title>
      <link>http://2022.computational-humanities-research/dates/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 19 Feb 2021 12:53:21 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://2022.computational-humanities-research/dates/</guid>
      <description>Submission deadline: Midnight (AoE), September 6, 2022
Notification to authors: October 18, 2022 
Final papers ready: November 1, 2022
Conference: December 12 - December 14, 2022</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Accepted Papers</title>
      <link>http://2022.computational-humanities-research/papers/</link>
      <pubDate>Sat, 01 Aug 2020 08:55:52 +0200</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://2022.computational-humanities-research/papers/</guid>
      <description></description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Advisory Board</title>
      <link>http://2022.computational-humanities-research/advisory-board/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 16 Dec 2019 21:22:17 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://2022.computational-humanities-research/advisory-board/</guid>
      <description>Tara Andrews - University of Vienna, Austria Maud Ehrmann - EPFL, Switzerland Leah Henrickson - Loughborough University, UK Mike Kestemont - University of Antwerp, Belgium Barbara McGillivray - University of Cambridge and The Alan Turing Institute, UK George Mikros - National and Kapodistrian University of Athens, Greece Kristoffer Nielbo - Aarhus University, Denmark Michael Piotrowski - University of Lausanne, Switzerland Tatjana Scheffler - University of Potsdam, Germany Ted Underwood - University of Illinois, U.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Join the Community</title>
      <link>http://2022.computational-humanities-research/community/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Dec 2019 11:12:28 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://2022.computational-humanities-research/community/</guid>
      <description>We cordially invite you and other interested parties to join the Computational Humanities Research forum! The forum serves as an asynchronous platform to discuss all ideas and questions related to computational humanities research. These can be in-depth discussions about fundamental topics and questions of the discipline, or very practical ones, for example about how best to tackle a certain technical (coding) problem. And everything in between. Come join!</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Join the Community</title>
      <link>http://2022.computational-humanities-research/contact/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Dec 2019 11:12:28 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://2022.computational-humanities-research/contact/</guid>
      <description>Community Please join our Computational Humanities Research forum! The forum serves as an asynchronous platform to discuss all ideas and questions related to computational humanities research. These can be in-depth discussions about fundamental topics and questions of the discipline, or very practical ones, for example about how best to tackle a certain technical (coding) problem. And everything in between. Come join!
Contact For questions, ideas, or support, contact the organizers or drop us a line on the forum.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Call for Papers</title>
      <link>http://2022.computational-humanities-research/cfp/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 15 Dec 2019 11:11:58 +0100</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://2022.computational-humanities-research/cfp/</guid>
      <description>Registration is now open In the arts and humanities, the use of computational, statistical, and mathematical approaches has considerably increased in recent years. This research is characterized by the use of formal methods and the construction of explicit, computational models. This includes quantitative, statistical approaches, but also more generally computational methods for processing and analyzing data, as well as theoretical reflections on these approaches. Despite the undeniable growth of this research area, many scholars still struggle to find suitable research-oriented venues to present and publish computational work that does not lose sight of traditional modes of inquiry in the arts and humanities.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>CHR2022 Programme</title>
      <link>http://2022.computational-humanities-research/programme/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>http://2022.computational-humanities-research/programme/</guid>
      <description>Please note that all times are in Central European Time (CET)
Monday 12 December 2022 (Day 1)  (15:30-16:15: walk-in, registration) 16:15-16:30: welcome 16:30-18:00: session 1A: keynote Peter Turchin 18:00: opening reception (followed by self-paid dinner)  Tuesday 13 December 2022 (Day 2)  09:00-10:30: session 2A: Language 10:30-11:00: coffee break 11:00-12:20: session 2B: Literature I 12:30-13:30: lunch 13:30-15:00: sessions 2C: Images and Scans 15:00-15:30: coffee break 15:30-16:15: session 2D: Social Media 16:15-17:45: session 2E: poster pitch session, followed by walk-around 19:00: conference dinner (University club)  Wednesday 14 December 2022 (Day 3)  09:00-10:30: session 3A: keynote Nina Tahmasebi 10:30-11:00: coffee break 11:00-12:25: session 3B: Historical Dynamics 12:30-13:30: lunch 13:30-15:05: sessions 3C: Literature II 15:05-15:35: coffee break 15:35-17:05: session 3D: Text Classification 17:05-17:30: session 3E: award ceremony, concluding remarks   Detailed Programme Session 2A Language picture_as_pdf  The Roots of Doubt.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
